rabobankamerica.com 2015-03-15

# Rabobank, N.A. Consumer Privacy Policy

## Rabobank, N.A. Consumer Privacy Policy

Effective December 1, 2014

What does Rabobank do with your information?  
---  
Why? | Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.   
What? | The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Social Security Number and Income
  * Account Balances and Payment History
  * Credit History and Credit Score

How? | All financial companies need to share customers' personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers' personal information; the reasons Rabobank, N.A. chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.  
Reasons we can share your personal information | Does Rabobank, N.A. share? | Can you limit this sharing?  
---|---|---  
**For our everyday business purposes** —  
such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus  | Yes | No  
**For our marketing purposes** —  
to offer our products and services to you  | Yes | No  
**For joint marketing with other financial companies** | Yes | Yes  
**For our affiliates' everyday business purposes** —  
information about your transactions and experiences  | Yes | No  
**For our affiliates' everyday business purposes** —  
information about your creditworthiness  | No | We Don't Share  
**For nonaffiliates to market to you** | No | We Don't Share  
To limit our sharing  
---  
To limit our sharing | 

  * Call 800-942-6222. Our menu will prompt you through your choice(s)
  * Mail the form found in the Rabobank, N.A. Privacy Policy document.

**Please note:**

If you are a new customer, we can begin sharing your information 30 days from the date we sent this notice. When you are no longer our customer, we continue to share your information as described in this notice.

However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.  
  
Questions | Call 800-942-6222  
Who we are  
---  
Who is providing this notice? | Rabobank, N.A.  
What we do  
---  
How does Rabobank, N.A. protect my personal information? | To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.

Further, we maintain strict internal policies and procedural safeguards against unauthorized use or disclosure of Customer information.  
  
How does Rabobank, N.A. collect my personal information? | We collect your personal information, for example, when you: 

  * open an account or apply for a loan
  * pay your bills or use your credit or debit card
  * make deposits or withdrawals from your account

We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus or other companies.  
Why can't I limit all sharing? | Federal law gives you the right to limit only: 

  * sharing for affiliates' everyday business purposes—information about your creditworthiness
  * affiliates from using your information to market to you
  * sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing. See below for more on your rights.  
What happens when I limit sharing for an account I hold jointly with someone else? | Your choice will apply to all of your accounts and everyone on your accounts.  
Defintions   
---  
Affiliates | Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies. 

  * _Our affiliates include companies with a Rabobank name and financial companies such as De Lage Landen and Rabo AgriFinance._

Nonaffiliates | Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies. 

  * _Rabobank, N.A. does not share with nonaffiliates so they can market to you._

Joint Marketing | A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you. 

  * _Our joint marketing partners include companies such as Elan Financial Services, a joint credit card provider._

Other important information  
---  
  
**Do Not Call Policy.** This notice is the Rabobank, N.A. Do Not Call Policy under the Telephone Consumer Protection Act. We do not solicit via telephone numbers listed on the state or federal Do Not Call lists, unless the law allows. Rabobank, N.A. employees receive training on how to document and process telephone marketing choices. Consumers who ask not to receive telephone solicitations from Rabobank, N.A. will be placed on the Rabobank, N.A. Do Not Call list and will not be called in any future campaigns, including those of Rabobank, N.A. affiliates. If you communicate with us by telephone, we may monitor or record the call.

**California:** California law gives you the right to opt out of certain sharing. Please see the enclosed notice entitled "Important Privacy Choice for Consumers".  
  
Do you have questions? Call (888) 945-6600 for more information or visit your local branch. 

Read our Online Privacy Policy.
